Matt JAQUIERY

PERSONAL

My principal interests are encountering, exploring, and communicating ideas. I am especially interested in how and why people behave the way they do, and what (if any) role consciousness has to play.

Having studied literature, philosophy, and science, I feel the scientific method offers the most promising approach to providing practical explanations, though the interpretation of results frequently requires philosophical analysis, especially when working on consciousness.

These advantages of science require a vigorous and continued vigilance to ensure empirical tests are robust. I am actively involved in Open Science, continually looking for ways to ensure my scientific output is more reliable and help others do likewise.

matt.jaquiery@psy.ox.ac.uk

99, Flat B, Copse Lane, Marston, Oxford, OX3 0AU

+44 7397 902010



0000-0003-3599-1580



osf.io/bc9xt/



mjaquiery



VerySmallDreams.com



mjaquiery

PUBLICATIONS

Rahnev, D., ..., Jaquiery, M., ... (in prep) Confidence database

Calder-Travis, J., Charles, L., **Jaquiery, M**., Carlebach, N., Yeung, N. (*in prep*). Relative contributions of positive and negative evidence to confidence ratings

Gyurkovics, M., Kovacs, M., Aczel, B., Palfi, B., **Jaquiery, M.** (*stage 1 in principle acceptance from* Attention, Perception, & Psychophysics, *2019*). Registered Replication Report of Weissman, D. H., Jiang, J., & Egner, T. (2014). Determinants of congruency sequence effects without learning and memory confounds. Journal of Experimental Psychology: Human Perception and Performance, 40(5), 2022-2037.

Martin, A.M., Maughan, B., **Jaquiery. M.**, Barker, E.D. (*in prep*). Positive father behaviour moderates the relationship between maternal depression and child behavioural and emotional problems

Kleyn, L.M., Wölfer, R., Hewstone, M.R., **Jaquiery, M.**, Ward, C. (*in prep*). Investigating the Impact of a Parenting Intervention within a Rural South African Community: a Social Network Analysis

Chrisley, R. and **Jaquiery, M.** (2018). Trajectory change blindness: What might it tell us about the temporal character of visual experience?, paper presented to Association for the Scientific Study of Consciousness (ASSC22), Kraków, 26-9 June 2018.

PROJECTS

A Crowdsourced Effort to Develop a Lab Manual Template for Social and Behavioural Scientists – **Contributor**

UKRN Primer – Preprints - Author
UKRN Primer – Data sharing – Author

AWARDS

2017

The Sussex Neuroscience Prize for best MRes dissertation

EDUCATION

2017-present DPhil Experimental Psychology Oxford University

Supervisor: Nick Yeung

2016-2017 MRes Neuroscience University of Sussex

Grade: Distinction (83%) - Dissertation 1: 87% / Dissertation 2: 84%

2013-2016 B.Sc. (Hons.) Neuroscience with Cognitive Science University of Sussex

Weighted Mean: 76% - Dissertation: 87% (Dr. Ron Chrisley; Dr. Paul Graham)

2009-2012 B.A. (Hons.) English Literature Open University

First Class Degree

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

The Eye's Mind – Prof. **Adam Zeman**, Cognitive Neurology Research Group, Exeter University Honorary Postgraduate Research Assistant (June-December 2016)

Developed custom software to process the content of thousands of aphantasia questionnaires encoded in .doc format into a data structure suitable for analysis.

http://medicine.exeter.ac.uk/research/healthresearch/cognitive-neurology/

Analytical Tool Development – Prof. Guy Richardson (FRS), Sussex University (Spring 2015)

Developed and shared programs for analysing electrophysiology traces. The shared versions extracted frequency and amplitude analysis of spikes. One program was extended for personal use to conduct more thorough analysis as part of a project write-up.

"Thank you for creating the spikeAnalyser and legUp programs for our 2nd year *Techniques in Neuroscience* course. I had been looking for someone who could do this for me for a least a couple of years and no-one had risen to the challenge until you, as a student on the course, clearly realised the necessity and went off and did the job, not only of your own accord but also within a remarkably short amount of time. It was a real pleasure interacting with you on this project; your responses to my feedback and suggestions were implemented with remarkable efficiency and I have no doubt we will be using your programs and the user guides you have written for many years to come. Your help has been invaluable and I can't thank you enough."

g.p.richardson@sussex.ac.uk

Computational Model Visualisation Project - Dr. Thomas Wennekers, Plymouth University

Voluntary Research Assistant (Summer 2015)

Approached Dr. Wennekers about summer work experience in his lab, leading to my developing a Python program to produce heatmap animations from computational models of neural activity. Provided detailed instructions for rendering the output on a 3D brain model in the 3D modelling software and rendering engine Blender.

thomas.wennekers@plymouth.ac.uk

EMPLOYMENT

2018-present Web developer/admin – Reproducible Research Oxford

Developing, deploying, and maintaining the web presence for Reproducible Research Oxford (https://ox.ukrn.org), allowing visitors interested in reproducible research practices to find relevant people and events. Involves collaboration with the wider UK Reproducibility Network.

2017-present Research Assistant - MultiSense (Simner & Ward) Lab, University of Sussex

Conducting research into aphantasia using a mixture of online experiments and reanalysis of large existing datasets.

2005-2015 Web Hosting Administrator – Self Employed

Developing, maintaining, and administrating websites and email accounts, including PHP/MySQL development work. Educating clients on the possibilities of web-based presentation and allowing them to reach informed choices about the details of their web presence. Interfacing with technical documentation, for example 3rd-party billing software.

2008-2009 Childminder – afterschool care, 4-6 children aged 5-11

Cooking for, listening to, and entertaining children after school. The challenges of this work were largely mollified by the intelligent and kind personalities of the children involved.

2006-2008

GCSE/A-Level Tutor – Various students in subjects including English and Maths Finding new ways for struggling students to interact with and understand their work.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

- Demonstrating and marking undergraduate practical experiments.
- Volunteer tutor with Oxford International Summer School providing 14-18 year old students with experience of Oxbridge tutorials. I designed and delivered a two-week course on perceptual psychology and the philosophy of mind.
- Completed divisional tutorial- and lecture-focussed training programmes.
- Tutoring and assisting undergraduate peers in their degree work to the extent permitted by university academic guidelines.
- Tutoring children and adolescents in one-to-one or small group settings on subjects including English, Maths, and Sciences.

PUBLIC ENGAGEMENT

Volunteer demonstrator for Experimental Psychology stand at Ideas Festival Oxford 2018

OTHER RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

- **Psychology Football** organiser, helping schedule a weekly kickabout to provide some exercise and entertainment for hard-working psychologists and academics in related fields
- Monday Maths organiser, helping psychologists get to grips with mathematical aspects of their work
- **ReproducibiliTea** organiser, helping ensure the ReproducibiliTea journal club runs smoothly and continues to spread to other universities and support open science.
- **Open Science Committee** member, helping Oxford Experimental Psychology integrate reproducible and open science practices into their work and teaching
- Experimental Psychology Theoretical Maths Club organizer, helping bring together
 Oxford Experimental Psychology graduate students and ECRs with an interest in exploring
 mathematics
- ReproducibiliTea Journal Club facilitator, leading discussions on papers addressing various issues with and aspects of open and reproducible research
- Assisting with organization of the Oxford Reproducibility School 2018 conference
- Student Rep for Taught Postgraduate Neuroscience, 2016-17
- Committee member for 'University of Sussex Polymath Society', an interdisciplinary presentation and discussion forum, 2015-17 (http://www.sussexstudent.com/organisation/polymath/)
- Wrote and delivered presentations on a range of discussion topics for the aforementioned society

RESEARCH SKILLS

- Data analysis (including Big Data in R; IBM SPSS statistics package)
- Programming (including MATLAB, R, Python, PHP, C#, and JavaScript/CSS/HTML)
- Presenting to multi-level audiences
- High-level writing skills

REFERENCES

Prof. Nick Yeung. Department of Experimental Psychology, University of Oxford Tel: +44 1865 271389 Email: nicholas.yeung@psy.ox.ac.uk
Prof. Kevin Staras. School of Life Sciences, University of Sussex, Brighton BN1 9QG Tel: +44 1273 678478 Email: K.Staras@sussex.ac.uk